Janardhan Shitole

Front-End Developer

Passionate Frontend Developer with overall 4 years of IT industry experience. Hands on experience with the concepts and implementations of HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap3&4, Javascript, AJAX, ES6, Flex and Angular, Angular material. Eagerly expanding skills into Backend, dedicated to ongoing learning and staying abreast of industry trends for proactive Developers.

+919049826265

Nagpur, India

https://vercel.com/karans-projects-4fb5dddf

https://www.linkedin.com/in/janardhan-shitole-257ba02a8/

https://github.com/karanshitole?tab=repositories

WORK EXPERIENCE :

Frontend Angular Developer

G-digitI nfotech

08/2022- Present Nagpur, India

Key roles and responsibilities:

- Led the front-end development for an E-commerce domain, ensuring a seamless and user-friendly experience. The major service include sales of electrical accessories like transformers, solar panels, motors and batteries.
- Created different modules, components using Angular Material, pipes and directives in angular as per business requirements.
- Implemented responsive wed design techniques to ensure that the e-commerce website functions well across various
 device and screen sizes, providing a consistent user experience on desktops, tablets and smartphones.
- Implements of different types of Quotation forms using reactive forms in angular and TD forms for Login and Signup component.
- Optimized the frontend performance by applying best practices such as code splitting, lazy loading, and caching.
- Monitor and analyze website performance metrics (e.g. page load time, time to interact) to identify and address
 performance bottlenecks Overcame data integration challenges in the user module implementing a custom API, ensuring
 accurate and up to date information to users.

Front End UI Developer

G-digit Infotech

08/2021- 08/2022 Nagpur, India

Key roles and responsibilities:

- Converted PSD into responsive HTML using Bootstrap 3
- Created interactions using JavaScript / jquery.
- Coordinate with a team of UX and UI developers to build quality web-applications with cross-browser compatibility.
- Responsive website for browser & environmental compatibility on every devices.
- Used Fetch APIs for communication with backend and database and also created interactions using javascript.

Application Support Engineer

G-digit Infotech

07/2020-08/2021 Nagpu

Keyroles and responsibilities:

- Coordinated with Level 1 technical support specialists to take over calls outside their level of support.
- Assisted customers with more difficult technical issues requiring a greater level of personalized care and in greater length.
- Diagnose and troubleshoot software and hardware problems and help our clients install applications and programs.
- Escalated support desk tickets to Level 3 in the most crucial circumstances.
- On boarded and trained all incoming junior tech support specialists.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Contributed Ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements in the angular project received positive feedback from users, leading to 15% increase in user engagement.
- Received a lot of appreciation from the team for quick learning and implementation.
- Received a lot of appreciation from the client for smooth delivery of the project.

| <u>SKILLS</u> : | Angular 10 | | Angular Material | | ypeScript | JavaScript, ES6 | | CSS | 3 |
|-----------------|--|--------|------------------|----------------|-----------|-----------------|------------|-------------|---|
| | SASS | HTML5 | HTML5 Bootstra | | AJAX | NGBootstrap | | FLEX | |
| | RXJS | jQuery | NPM | GIT/GITH | HUB RW | 'D Me | edia Queri | es | |
| TOOLS : | Visual studio Code Vercel Postman Firebase Jira jQuery-Plugins | | | | | | | | |
| | Augury | Chrome | Developer | Developer Tool | | ANGULAR-CLI | | FontAwesome | |

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Engineering

SRTMU Nanded

LANGUAGES

Marathi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Hind

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Nagpur, India